Guide to the Association for Case Teaching Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Publications, 1983-2001; Series IV
  - Case Studies
    - Mark - Martyr (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Marketing the Metric System Marriage license: a scrap of paper Marriage of Mary and Albert Married woman now Martin Luther king: justice, peace, and civil rights Martyr
    - Mary - Matter (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Mary Daly and Boston college Mary Gardner's fourth pregnancy Mass for Dr. Bryan, Protestant Matter of integrity Matter of life and death Matter of pride (a) & (b) Matter of principle
    - Max - Meth (Box 9, Folder 1)
      "Maxie Register and the Rotary Club" Mcnair on cases Membership committee Memo on Session with Section E Mennonites and capital punishment Methodist federation for social service
    - Metro - Midw (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Metropolitan Tulsa transit authority: affirmative action assurance plan The Metropolitan Development Corporation (a), (c), & (d) Michele Mid-western printing, Inc. Middle management ignored Mid-Western Printing Incorporated Midwestern university library (a), (b), (c), (d), & (e)
    - Mike - Mis (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Mike Smith, CPA, and the California farm labor problem Mineral Resources, Inc. A miserable failure Mission enterprise loan and investment committee
    - Mo (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Monkeys are restless, The Monroe County United Ministries The Montanist issue in the late second century More light? Motivation and promotion Mozambique mission
    - Mr - Nei (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Mr. Pete's My brother the slave National Council of Churches vs. Gulf and Western Needed but unwanted minister Neighbors, friends, decisions
    - Nev - Nice (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Never say die (a) & (b) New Lebanon convention of 1827 The New Pastor and the Choir Director New York teachers' walkout 1967 A nice kid with a birth defect
    - Nicene - Note (Box 9, Folder 7)
      The Nicene Creed No room at the inn Not in My Backyard Not in this church A Note on the US Prescription Drug Industry
    - Notes - Oi (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Notes on Religion in America Nowhere to lay his head Nuptial knots in Oneonta Obedience Oil and the Caribou People
    - Ol - On (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Old Cambridge Baptist Church (a) & (b) Old piet One hundred thousand dollar gift One nation, two gods One time too many
    - Op - Ou (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Open or closed Operation reach-out The ordination of Clare Ross Organ at Parkway Church Origins of the Second Helvetic Confession Outstanding clergyman of the year
    - Pan - Par (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Pants suits in church Parable interpretation: western or eastern style Parenting for peace and justice Participative planning and goal-setting in rural Ecuador
    - Pas - Pea (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Pastor under attack Pastoral change? (a) &(b) The Pattersons at Northfield Patton problem Paul and the Corinthians (a), (b) & (c) Peace child Peace Lutheran Church (a) & (b) Peacemaking in a local parish
    - Pen - Phil (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Pentecostal controversy in the National Association of Evangelicals People of hope (a) & (b) Peripatetic prostitute Phil Greenfield and the New Falls Church
    - Philis - Phy (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Philistine challenge Phillip Lancaster Phoebe Palmer and the ministry of women "Phyllis Crowder is Pregnant!"
    - Pl - Pn (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Planning for a congregation (a) & (b) Planning Monday (a) & (b) Plant closure project Please fire Mrs. Williams Pneumonia: friend or foe?
    - Po - Pre (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Polaroid experiment in South Africa Portrait of a Servant Power for peace Power through piety: Mother Seton, saint Prairie Storm Pray for a miracle Precipitate action: Jai Chandra's diary (5)
    - Proc - Prop (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Proclaim the good news Professor Tom Boyce Project Bible: the marketing of the book Prolonging life? Prophet or provocateur Prophet's letter
    - Prov - Ready (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Provincial's dilemma Psychology Today questionnaire (a) & (b) Queen of Peace Question of pastoral concern Raised in the Spirit Raising flak--or flag: Southside Community Church Rate breaker Ready for ministry?
    - Real - Rel (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Real estate investors Reasonable request? Red jacket and the missionary Reinhold Niebuhr and world war Religion under Communism: Patriarch Tikhon Renew a right spirit among us Religious Adolescence
    - Res - Ric (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Resignation (a) & (b) Resist or surrender? Return to celibacy? Returning home Rev. Anderson and the Sheraton Community Organization Richard Allen and the birth of the AME Church Rick Montrose (a) & (b)
    - Rig - Robert (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Right to Libel The Righteousness of God, Judgment, and Pauline Polity Rigor and responsibility Riverside presbytery (a) & (b) Riverton schools Robert Farmer, cancer patient (a), (b) & (c) Robert Rainy and "a larger Presbyterianism"
    - Roberto - Sac (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Roberto de Nobili: an example of missionary identification Rockville Church (a) & (b) Roger Cottle, embezzler Rosemary Radford Ruether RR railroad co. Sacred Heart Hospital's sterilization policy Sacred sites
    - Sam - Sem (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Sam Morton Sanctuary The search committee Search for meaning Second marriage A secondary manifestation Seminar for people's representatives Seminarian and the bank robbery
    - Sermon (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Sermon for first Sunday after Christmas Sermon for second Sunday in advent Sermon for third Sunday in advent Sermon for fourth Sunday in advent
    - Serv - Shall (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Service or sacrifice Servicing Beau Thompson Sex and Otto Schwinn (a), (b), & (c) Sgt. Boone, alcohol, and sex Shakers-- salvation and daily work Shaking hand: Jai Chandra's diary (1) Shall I marry them or not? (a), (b), & (c)
    - Shar - Sho (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Sharon Bates (a) & (b) Sherry Ambler...doctrinaire? Should I accept? "Should I baptize them... Now?" Should Tom work with our children (a) & (b)
    - Shi - Sk (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Shrimp Futures Silver bay Sing the Lord's Song Sins of parents (a) & (b) Skelly family and Akira Nagano
    - Small (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Small city (a): suit Small city (b): ordinance Small city (c): the election campaign Small city (d): the committee Small city (e): the council
    - Sn - St. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      A snake in the grass So close Socialist (a) & (b) Society of saints, or school for sinners? Solex Split devotion St. Paul's United Church of Christ (a), (b), & (c)
    - Sta - Ste (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Staff of St. Peter's Church Stand up and be counted (a) & (b) State college Stevens v. Parket, Davis & co. And A. J. Beland, M.D.: evaluation of prescription drug promotion and distribution practices Stewart Grow
    - Sto -Sui (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Story of Harold Geneen's I.T.T. Struggle and consent Stuart James Williams Student-worker program Sturm, Ruger & Co., Inc. Suffer the Little Children Suicide of Oliver Kendall (a) &(b)
    - Sus - Sy (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Susan B. Anthony and the Rights of Women Susan's call Suzanne Elliott Swane Motors, Inc. Synod of Dort and the Arminian controversy
    - Ta - Tec (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Tabb street Church (a), (b) & (c) Taylors and the teaching position Teaching genesis (a) & (b) Tearless acceptance Tectank, Inc. (C-1)
    - Tem - Thomas (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Temple-eastex, Inc. Text and context They said "no" to Sharice Thomas family goes private Thomas Perkins, short-term missionary
    - Thomp - To Be (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Thompsons and their paraplegic son Three hours late Time to stay and a time to go Timothy Leary and the psychedelic drugs To be or not to be a pastor (a) & (b)
    - To bear - To move (Box 12, Folder 3)
      To bear arms To declare or not to declare To drink or not: case about attitudes toward alcohol To every creature To leave or not to leave? To marry or not to marry? To move or not to move
    - To our - Tom (Box 12, Folder 4)
      To our own land To pray or not to pray To supervise or not Toast for Bob Allison Tom Prince and the problem of professional conduct
    - Tom's - Tra (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Tom's choice Toward Pluralism Transformation: Jai Chandra's diary (3) Traveling for transformation
    - Tri - Turna (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Trial of Emily Richardson Trinity Church and the ministerial candidate Trouble in Togo land Troubled Internship Turnaround management
    - Turner - United B (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Turner Greene Twilight or dawn? Two churches later Unhappy hooker United Baptist Church
    - United C - United M (Box 12, Folder 8)
      United Church (a) United Methodist Church
    - United P - Va (Box 12, Folder 9)
      United parish in Brookline United products, Inc. University Church Vapco (a) & (b)
    - Vi - Wal (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Vietnam's children Visions and realities Walker hardware co. (a) & (b) Wallace king: D-Min coup de grace or cul de sac Walnut Avenue Church Walter Rauschenbusch and the social awakening of the churches
    - War - We (Box 12, Folder 11)
      The warden's dilemma (a) (b) & (c) Warrens and Mabel Washington Gladden (1836-1918) We just can't go on meeting like this "We want to be pacifists, too!" ... Paraguay's law #514
    - We're - Westfield (Box 12, Folder 12)
      We're going down, Larry Wedding committee Westbridge Village Congregational Church Westfield Church (a) & (b)
    - Western - Westport (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Western Bell and the Communications Workers of America Westhills Westport grass
    - What - When ecumenical (Box 12, Folder 14)
      What Awakens Student Interest in a Case What Kind of God? What shall it profit us? What should I do, chaplain? What to pray? What's the limit? What's the matter, Abdaraman? (a) & (b) When ecumenical relations cool
    - When in - Whither (Box 13, Folder 7)
      When in Northumbria, do as the Romans do? The Synod of Whitby (A.D. 664) When the congregational meeting erupted (a) & (b) Where was God Tuesday morning (a) & (b) Which way is home? Whipps Mill Seniors White paint for Green River Whither the people of God?
    - Who - Wiltshire (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Who is he? Who picked up the check? Who will pastor our churches Whose failure is it? Whose life to save? Why Globalization? Wiltshire Methodist Church
    - Wimble - Women's (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Wimble Park Witness, The Witchcraft at Salem Wittenberg 1934 A woman's place Women's theological center
    - World - Yank (Box 13, Folder 10)
      World Council of Churches: fifth assembly--Nairobi World hunger, the First Baptist Church, and the Sandinistas Worldwide machinery corp. (a) & (b) Worthington department stores Yank who wouldn't go home
    - Yash - Ze (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Yash Pal's family plan: case of an enterprising client You Must Purify This House "Your daughter, a minister?" Youth elder for Oak Brook Zerubbabel: to build or not to build a temple
    - Manual on Ministry (case collection) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Air Force Case Collection (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - ACT Newsletter
    - ACT Newsletter, 1983-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - ACT Newsletter, 1990-2005 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re. ACT Newsletter, 1990-1994 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Other publications
    - Articles in Together: A Journal of World Vision International, 1985-6 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Bibliography Update 1986, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - ACT Brochures (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Journal for Case Teaching No. 2, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re. Journal of Case Teaching (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence re. copyright (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Index of Cases in Christian Mission (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - ACT Website, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- ACT Distributed Materials, Series V
  - Learning from Cases (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Learning by the Case Method How to Study a Case Cases in Conflict Resolution: What they are and how to study them An Introduction to the case method Note on the Use of the Case Method The use of cases in Management Education Approach to case analysis
  - Teaching Cases (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Teaching by the Case Method Teaching Diaries
  - Teaching Cases (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Use of case material in the classroom Uses of cases in executive education Ideas for Improving Supervised Ministry Cases Suggestions for teaching a case Suggestions for case teaching coaches "Writing and Teaching Cases" from The Journal for Case Teaching Preparation to Teach a Case Case Methodology Teaching Cases and Concepts – The Twain do meet Course Development Policy Course Approach: De Paul Case Analysis Evaluating a Case Course: Performance Criteria
  - Writing Cases (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Cases Which Meet the Student's Needs Developing Cases from Written Sources Writing your first case Writing Cases summary "Writing and Teaching Cases" from The Journal for Case Teaching Discussion Outline for Case Writing Writing and teaching cases Writing a case and its teaching note Case development and the teaching note Writing Business Cases Some Suggestions for Writing a Business Case
  - Case Study Research (Box 13, Folder 16)
    Preparation of Case Material -So They're Writing a Case… About You! When the case study man calls
  - Case Processing (samples) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Case Collection (Box 13, Folder 18)
    Preparing a Set of Cases Case collection procedures Case Collection Sample (Asia)
  - Case Teaching Advocacy (Box 13, Folder 19)
    The Emergence of Case Method Teaching 1870s-1990s The Language Circle: Inside the Teaching and Learning of Language "Now, Go" Christianity, Modernization, and Education: A Case Method Approach Theological Education and the Case Method "Asking Questions is the Key Skill needed for Discussion Teaching" Because wisdom can't be told College Teaching by the 'Case Method' Cases: What they are and how to study them Tough-mindedness and the case method The usefulness of the case method for training in administration Managerial problem-solving and the case method
  - Sample forms (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Addendum: Files Received from Executive Directors, Series VI
  - Membership
    - Membership lists, 1985, 1992, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Membership letters and application forms, 1988–1998 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Organization and policy records
    This subseries contains correspondence and documentation from the files of ACT Co-Executive Directors Robert Evans and Alice Frazer Evans.
    - Historical statement, formative documents, 1974, no date (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1979–1982 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1986–1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, documents, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, documents, 2000–2001 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, documents, 2002–2003 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, documents, 2014 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence regarding tax status, Internal Revenue Service, 1979–2014 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Workshops and institutes
    - Directory of Fellows - Case-Study Institute Summer Workshops, 1972–1975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Case Study Institute Summer Workshop, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Case Study Institute Summer Workshops, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1974–1977 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Case Study Institute Summer Workshops and staff meetings, Fuller Theological Seminary, Pasadena, California, 1978–1980 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Case Study Institute Summer Workshops, Wake Forest, North Carolina, 1981–1982 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Additional summer institutes, 1983–1993 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Additional summer institutes, 1994–2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Short term institutes, workshops, 1972–1989 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Workshops and institutes led by Robert and Alice Evans, including in Indonesia and South Africa, 2001-2002, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Publications
    - Case studies
      - Cases in Theological Education: Bibliography, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 1,2)
      - Index of Case Studies in Christian Mission, by Alan Neely, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Chinese Case Studies, 2010–2013 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        These case studies were written during a porject titled "Risk Management for a Harmonious Society in mainland China. The principals were Plowshares Institute, based in Simsbury, Connecticut, and Civic Exchange in Hong Kong. The first cases were written by the international leaders and later cases by project partiicpants in universities in Beijing, Nanjing, and Shanghai.
      - Chinese Case Studies, 2010–2013 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous lists, abstracts, guides related to case study method, 1983–1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous lists, abstracts, guides related to case study method, 1887–1989 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Editing and mentoring correspondence, 1984–2007 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Association for Case Teaching Newsletter
      These are the issues of the newsletter received with the files of Robert and Alice Evans; additional issues are available in Series IV
      - ACT Newsletter, 1979–1982 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - ACT Newsletter, 1983–2001 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Other publications
      - Brochures, statements of purpose, 1989, no date (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Regarding Journal for Case Teaching, 1991–1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - "Peace Skills in Action" - a production of Plowshare Institute, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        VHS tape related to Community Conflict Transformation